# Michael F. Galloway

9263 Blackberry St. #3 | Anchorage, AK 99502 | +1(907)903-6336 |michael.galloway9@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Versatile and objective oriented leader with over 10 years of experience developing successful teams and implementing innovative processes to meet business requirements in the energy resource sector. Warehouse, Logistics, and Inventory Control experience in Supply Chain and Material Management. Supported Operations and Maintenance for on-shore oil field operations in Alaska and for off-shore operations in Trinidad and Tobago. Expert analytical skills with the ability to turn data into information. Proven aptitude for engaging and motivating teams. Delivers results and adds value by being proactive, resourceful, and diligent.

## PERFORMANCE AND RESULTS

## **Leadership and Management**

- Managed diverse team of 10 Professionals in all areas of Inventory Control Management
- Accountable for the performance and integrity of inventory valued at \$350M
- Responsible for inventory level gate keeping through the Material Amendment Proposal process
- Led inventory optimization efforts of cost avoidance, redeployment, and surplus of dormant inventory
- Responsible for approving inventory adjustments up to \$500K
- Led team of cycle count technicians in verifying more than 100K inventory records in a cycle
- Prioritized stock out reviews which led to 98.4% service levels prevented production loss and reduced safety risks to the field
- Managed 12 Trinidad and Tobago nationals in warehouse and inventory operations for off-shore platforms
- Delivered 97% conformance and 99% transaction accuracy for 1<sup>st</sup> stage receiving
- Managed 14 Warehouse Technicians in cross-dock operations supporting the North Slope Oil Field
- Led 6 member teams in cargo and ramp operations at the Anchorage International Airport

## **Project Execution**

- Strengthened the catalog's integrity by performing criticality conversion of legacy data to SAP
- Substantially reduced costs and number of records converted over to new ERP system by executing duplicate catalog item project
- Managed traceable material data clean-up efforts in ensuring proper data conversion
- Collaborated with Finance to successfully reconcile modified inventory account
- Mapped flow of multiple business processes, enabling safer and more efficient operations
- Participated in and completed numerous continuous improvement projects
- Made visible \$10M of project excess material, creating opportunities for redeployment vs. buying new
- Managed construction project of two warehouses from the ground up in Trinidad
- Executed 1.5 year plan of developing a local understudy to take over warehouse operations in Trinidad
- Worked with Operations in Trinidad to build critical spares inventory
- Completed several warehouse consolidation projects safely and efficiently

## **Strategy Development and Implementation**

- Developed cycle count program, delivering 96% item accuracy and 99% value accuracy
- Developed multiple reporting dashboards, communicating performance to high level executives
- Implemented batch management of Halon chemical bullets for better traceability
- Constructed work gueues in Optimizer to enable Inventory Specialists in performing top priorities
- Updated Optimizer cost model to ensure accurate recommendations of inventory levels to the region
- Performed analysis on various business data to support business decisions and work planning
- Designed document repository for project excess and implemented sustainable turn-in process
- Simplified and streamlined modified inventory account and fabrication processes
- Created and maintained numerous operating procedures
- Developed in-depth training program for onboarding new Inventory Control Team members

Michael F. Galloway Page 2

#### **DISCIPLINE EXPERIENCE**

Supply Chain Management Performance Management Project Management

**Inventory Optimization** 

Standard Operating Procedure Development

Data Management Root Cause Analysis

Continuous Improvement Execution

#### **PROFESSIONAL HISTORY**

Advanced Supply Chain International Material Handling Technician 2004 to 2006  Alaska Airlines Cargo & Ramp Agent/Lead 2001 to 2004	Advanced Supply Chain International Internatio	Acting BP Material Control Team Lead Material Control Lead Material Control Performance Analyst Project Excess Coordinator Warehouse & Inventory Manager (Trinidad) Anchorage Cross-Dock and Facility Manager Material Handling Technician Cargo & Bamp Agent/Lead	2013 to present 2012 to present 2011 to 2012 2009 to 2011 2007 to 2009 2006 to 2007 2004 to 2004 to 2004
---	--	--	--

## **TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE**

**Enterprise Resource Planning Applications** 

- SAP (ECC, SRM)
- Maximo
- **CMMS** Passport

## **Business Analytics Applications**

- **Business Objects**
- Business Warehouse
- Brio Intelligence
- OAS Optimizer

# **Supply Chain Specific Applications**

ASCI Smart Tools Suite – SmartStager, SmartCatalog, SmartTracker, DocAdvance

## TRAINING

Bovo Tighe Leadership Training Train the Trainer 49CFR Hazmat Quality Receiving Program

Mind Map Management **NSTC** Training Microsoft Office Suite Courses

## **EDUCATION**

Southwestern College, Chula Vista, CA General Studies

**Shoreline Community College General Studies**